so let's do the math how long have you
been now been playing
like eight months eight months have you
played any matches you know what i mean
by that
no points nothing do you know how to
keep score no
i mean i've heard about like love
all right 15. 15.
40 and 45 45. oh i'm gonna teach you
sure no i'm going to teach you the whole
thing today i want to prepare you for
your first match here's my idea
i want to teach you how to play like how
to keep score
all the rules and everything then we're
going to talk about tactics like how
you're actually going to play
and i'm going to put it to test and play
your first match ever um we've got to
find someone
we got to find someone for you to play
against and then because
you have to play i mean you
you don't necessarily have to you could
all like just play tennis
um and just rally and all that and do
drills
but you need like you're missing out on
a big
aspect of tennis was the actual
competition it's the one-on-one you
compete against somebody else so anna
like when you end up winning
a match it's gonna feel so good you're
gonna be so happy it's gonna be like
walking on clouds however if you end up
losing it's gonna feel
terrible too so that's the fun of it
like the competitive aspect of tennis is
so fun
and i do want you to to experience that
so i would like you to start playing
some matches
and i'm gonna prepare you for it okay i
don't think i'm gonna feel bad if i lose
some people don't depends on the
personality like i personally
when i lose you get this stuff like
that's an understatement
i get extremely extremely yeah i'm not
very good when i lose
not very good for about two days
i'm i'm in a really really bad mood but
then after that i kind of
the nice thing about tennis is always
the next match is always the next
tournament
and you kind of kind of forget about the
loss
but yeah i'm not i'm not very good at
losing but some people are some people
can just shake it off immediately and
they're happy and
i think you are one of those people
because i have competitions in dancing
yeah here's your grip most of the time
i like that it matches nice and we are
matching grips look we have both of the
same grips
nice all right so i'm gonna explain to
you how the scoring system first works
okay
so go ahead and stay on the baseline
okay anna so the way
scoring works in tennis basically
consists of a point
a game a set and a match
point game set match
you know when they say game set match
okay they said at the end of a match
that means it's over somebody won a
match is so it's a whole thing okay
so a point basically you see this middle
a line right here it's called a baseline
hash i think i'm not sure about that but
you're always going to start from the
right okay you're gonna start from the
right
and you're gonna serve into the left
there you gotta get into that box you
see the box right there
service line you know that okay so
okay then after every point you're gonna
switch
so it's very important you start on you
start always start on this side
serving from the right to the left now
the way
the points work is kind of weird in
tennis because you need four points to
win a game
and this comes from the french they used
to keep score by using a clock
so the clock they would go 15 love which
is one point
30 love which is two points
then you would think it would go 45 love
and then game but the problem is
what if you tie at 45 all
you need two points to win the game and
that's why they say 40
because 40 would go up to 51 points and
then another
another point would be 60. does that
make sense so it doesn't go
15 30 45 it goes 15 30
40 because at 40 it's called deuce
and you need two points to win that
makes sense
yes and then when it's zero you say love
which means love
in in uh french which means uh egg so
it's kind of like a zero i guess
oh yeah so you say love all right so we
got 15 love 30 love
40 love not 45 and then and then we have
game so four points
if you tie the three points that's
called deuce
and then you have to win two points
you're gonna have
either add in or add out so let's say
it's
add in and you lose the point it goes
back to deuce so it keeps going until
somebody wins two points in a row all
right so once that's over
i guess i have to experience it it's not
that
hard like once you learn it it's super
easy trust me all right
so now you have one game okay if you win
that game you have one game now it goes
up to six
games to win a set so you can win six
zero six one six two six three
or six four so if there are two people
playing the game what is the
longest game can go to like for example
if
the longest tennis match longest thing
is longest tennis match
was uh 11 hours yeah over 11 hours john
isner against nicolas mahuda wimbledon
yeah it was over 11 hours played over
three days so it can go on forever
yeah i can go on forever but i had to do
that they weren't playing tie breaks
i'll get to that later
so you have a set that goes to to six
okay set goes to six
if it's five all you go to seven if it's
six all
you play something called a tie break
all right and the tie break you have to
count
to seven but you don't count fifteen
left third left you just count regular
one uh and first one to get to seven
points win by two
all right so that's a set and we'll
practice tie breaks cyborgs are a little
bit complicated
i will practice those um just pray that
you don't get into a tie break your very
first set you play okay
that would be bad luck so then once you
win a set you need two sets to win the
match
so if you win two sets you win the match
okay you understand what it is
yes you sure because now i'm gonna put
you to the test okay
we're gonna do a test here's what you're
gonna do you're gonna serve
i'm gonna keep score for you if you make
your serve
right there you win the point if you
double fault you lose the point when is
the last time you served
okay here we go again you're not
following my recommendations you
probably won't i did i did the i
practice
you serve a couple times all right we'll
see we'll see in a minute if you have or
not
but anyway basically you're going to
keep score you play against no one but
you're still going to keep score and
practice that way okay
so we're going to get started it's love
love
first point let's see what happens
okay you're gonna keep score what is it
um i i don't know nobody was there
do you want the point just pretend
there's an opponent there you won the
point so it's 15
you missed the shot 15 0 15. no
15 love 15 love always the points are
scored from the server's perspective so
you're the server
you count your points first okay
all right 15. so if yeah if you would
have lost that point would have been
love 15.
all right next point now we got to
switch sides you got to go over there
15 love okay
second serve throw that ball a little
higher yeah
you lost that point it's all right now
switch sides again what's this oh you
can say 15 all
15 all a-l-l 15-all
toss is going behind you second serve
now you know you have two serves in
tennis i forgot to mention that yes so
if you missed the first one you got
another one
can i do that absolutely that's a lot
you can toss it and catch it
it's windy too it's very windy i know
lately it's been super windy
uh oh another double fault all right
let's go on to the next side score
what's the score 15 30.
that's right
it's all right it's all right come again
make sure you get a continental grip
that's out all right score
what's the score there's a big test 40
15 40. 15 40.
wow you're learning fast that's
unbelievable 15 40 go the other side now
you see what happens when you don't
practice serves you're going to lose
this game
all by double faults so you believe me
now how important the server is
very clutch nice yeah score
330 no no it was 15
30. it was 1540. oh was it 40 no
yes it was it was 1540. then 40 30.
no service perspective you're down 15
40.
30 40. okay all right go the other way
are you sure it wasn't 30.
i'm 1000 sure the imaginary opponent
still has what's called a break point
okay
he's got a break point break point
if you lose this game you've gotten
broken you're served broken
if you win this game you would hold your
serve
so it's called a break point your
opponent is about to break your serve
your service game gibberish
no come on this is tennis terminology
we're gonna learn it this is tennis
terminology you need to know this
come on
out second serve
and you got broken you lost the game
anna
four double faults we gotta practice the
serve more yeah
you gotta do give me do me a favor for
this match i need you to really ramp up
your surf practice
because you can't be double faulting
because you're gonna lose you're going
to lose
all your service points yeah this grip
is like not making me happy i like uh
you like forehand grip forehand grip
when i serve not allowed
you sure 100 1000
you need a continental grip you got to
go 10 practice all right now
you lost the game okay one zero that
means you have to switch sides with your
opponent
okay yeah every odd game you switch
sides
so what that means one zero you switch
then let's say you win that game or you
you win the game it's one one it's an
even number
one plus one two is even you don't
switch
let's say you win that game is two one
you switch sides again how many give the
total
three how long does a set go up till
it's a test i told you before a set goes
to what
until six okay six games all right this
is going to be a this is going to be a
great video
this is your preparation for the match a
lot of pressure
all right so now um we're gonna play
another game i'm gonna serve
and we'll see what happens now you're
returning okay so let me show you where
to stand on return okay
slide over there so important the other
person's gonna be serving okay
you're going to stand close to the
doubles alley
but like right here it's going to be
where you see your right foot is going
to be right here
now if that person has a really weak
serve you can stand inside
inside the baseline right here like this
and wait for the return so stand right
here
yeah a little bit more is the person who
is having a week
quick serve if the strap is a little bit
stronger you can back up okay but you
may be close to the
it won't be close to the single slide
this is the single slide no until i see
right what they're doing
how we how strong their service yeah you
would have to see it
once you see them served and then adjust
your positioning but always stand here
because
when somebody's serving from over there
uh they're gonna have a
from from your perspective a rightward
trajectory so you have to cover this
this
area right here so the ball is gonna
have a rightward trajectory that's why
you stand
close to the singles line you can't
stand too far in the middle
okay and it's gonna be a return of serve
so we're gonna count
up the same way you just play out the
points
out you know that was out right
so what's the score now that's right
always from the server's perspective
yeah all right here we go now you switch
sides
score okay
when you return and you hit that
forehand you go back to the middle
you can't stand in the corner there the
entire half is open there
okay so hit the return quickly go to the
middle of the court
all right come on this is real tennis
now
oh no
very strong return on him very strong
big power
score we didn't stage it actually i
couldn't
i would i wanted i wanted to make you
play i couldn't control my forehand
what's the score score okay
uh wow you're so smart
in that was a great shot by the way 30
all
right yeah right all right 30 off all
right here we go
very nice
no i missed it again too strong
by the way i saw you hanging out over
there again you got to go to the middle
anna
all right but you gotta practice you
know but that was a very strong see if
the forehand is you're gonna be your
your weapon so what's the score now
um 30 40. yes
30 40 and that's called what
break points so you got a break point
now this is huge
because you lost your serve you can
break right back and even the score
okay come on
you gotta stay out okay
second serve ah no
i got so tight that's what happened to
players
30 40 break point i got nervous and i
make a double fault
very common are you sleep deprived
what's the score now
big test let me check your score what is
it now
45 no oh no 30 45
no remember how like after 40 what goes
the game
four points so it's 30 40. you won three
points you want another point
that's game no 45
what's the score in games the first game
on your serve you lost it right yes
so zero one and now you won the second
game
okay what's the score so it's a tie it's
one one
one all right now you just keep going
like this you keep going okay
until somebody gets six unless it's five
all then you win by two it's up to seven
okay and if it's six all you play one
one it's just
you don't say it's a tie you don't say
tie you just say one all
you say one one off that's a set score
and then you just keep going until six
most likely when you play your first
match we're only gonna play one set
and a match consists of two sets you
have to win two sets
so it's 12 until 12. no
separate set so when you win the first
set let's say you win this
at 6-1 you play a second set starts back
at 0-0
okay if your opponent wins the second
set then you play a deciding third
set winner takes all all right now now
we talk tactics
come on give me a racket tap this is
going to be the most important talk
i know it's weird because you never this
scoring system is a little bit odd in
tennis
but like i said once you learn it's
going to be super easy yeah you have any
questions
it's all right if you get it wrong in
the beginning you know people will help
you we know what helps they're watching
tennis on tv
okay all right if you watch it on tv oh
you don't have tv
watch it on youtube okay i got a couple
of matches of mine you want to watch me
yes all right i'll send you my matches
and the score is right there on the
bottom
all right anna that's actually a good
thing to do before the match you warm up
you warm up and you you if you want to
stretch you can
but as far as tactics when it comes to
playing matches
it's going to be super simple all i want
you to do is just get the ball
into the cord like even down the middle
of the court it doesn't really matter
where you place it
like just pick the biggest target you
can get and just keep it in play
as much as you can don't try to hit hard
don't try to overpower the other person
just keep the ball in
what that will do is going to give you
confidence
in your strokes that eventually once you
start playing more matches you're going
to trust your shots more that you're
going to go
harder because what will happen i can
guarantee you that if you go out
and start kind of blasting the ball
start hitting hard
you're going to make tons of mistakes
you're going to lose okay right
so just got to keep it simple get it in
the serve
the ground strokes your 400 back end
just get it in nothing fancy
it can be slow now here's the good news
all the stuff that we do with technique
forget about it when you play a match
don't even spend one second thinking
about technique
because you can't get into my head and
miss everything because you can't anyway
you can't anyway think about um
technique when you play matches just
think of the actual match there's going
to be a lot of thoughts going through
your mind
you know you're going to want to win
right everybody wants to win and
your mind is going to be preoccupied
with that you're going to be feeling
different emotions such as
a little bit of anxiety at certain times
i don't know if you even felt it when we
did that exercise serving but you're
going to feel what they say intent is
tight
you're going to feel a little bit
anxious and nervous so all this stuff is
going to go through your mind
so there's no time to think about
technique all the stuff
that we do when we practice that stuff
is going to be there for you eventually
it's going to be in your muscle memory
it's going to be automated
and we worry about that on the practice
chord
when it comes to the match court you
completely free your mind from that
and just play the actual game
it's that whatever is there whatever is
that whatever is there is there
and don't even worry about it now we
haven't played for a month
your forehand uh went back a little bit
to the old way
that's something we're gonna work on
we're gonna play more now you and i i'm
gonna do a couple more sessions before
you first set
private sessions not on camera and
trying to get your forehand up to speed
so that
it's a little bit better for the match
and of course like i said before
don't ignore the serve the serve see how
it's often ignored
but you see how important it is in a
match yeah because you're either serving
or you're receiving it
huh it's a point and every every point
starts with a serve whether you're
serving or the other person's serving
do you have any questions about playing
matches i know you're kind of like
i don't see too much excitement even
though there was
you know like the thing is like for me
process of
uh the process and keeping the ball in
play
and moving my body and with somebody
else but you'll get that too in a match
situation there are going to be rallies
but the fun part is that you're actually
going to win the rally
you know somebody wins the rally and the
intention
and a point is to win the point where
the intention in a rally is to
keep the rally going to hit the other
person's a completely different
mindset when you play you're playing to
beat the other person
when you're just practicing you're
playing to have the other person
hit it back to you so that's going to be
the difference so
i want to awaken the killer instinct in
you
how much killer instinct you have now we
got to find somebody for you to play
with
all right anna let's do a racket tap
this is gonna be fun
your first match